[
{
  "question": "58. For your safety, when setting out reflective triangles you should:",
  "choices": [
      "Carry the triangles at your side.",
      "Hold the triangles between yourself and oncoming traffic.",
      "Keep them out of sight while you walk to the spots where you set them out."
  ],
  "answer": "Hold the triangles between yourself and oncoming traffic."
},
{
  "question": "59. Heavy vehicles must sometimes travel more slowly than other traffic. Which of these is NOT a good rule to follow when you are driving such a vehicle?",
  "choices": [
      "Signal other drivers when it is safe for them to pass you.",
      "Stay to the right.",
      "Turn on your flashers if it is legal to do so."
  ],
  "answer": "Signal other drivers when it is safe for them to pass you."
},
{
  "question": "60. The most important reason for being alert to hazards is so:",
  "choices": [
      "Accident reports will be accurate.",
      "Law enforcement personnel can be called.",
      "You will have time to plan your escape if the hazard becomes an emergency."
  ],
  "answer": "You will have time to plan your escape if the hazard becomes an emergency."
},
{
  "question": "61. Hydroplaning:",
  "choices": [
      "Cannot occur when driving through a puddle.",
      "Only occurs at speeds above 50 mph.",
      "Is more likely if tire pressure is low."
  ],
  "answer": "Is more likely if tire pressure is low."
},
{
  "question": "62. If you are being tailgated, you should:",
  "choices": [
      "Increase your following distance.",
      "Flash your brake lights.",
      "Signal the tailgater when it is safe to pass you."
  ],
  "answer": "Increase your following distance."
},
{
  "question": "63. Which of these statements about overhead clearance is true?",
  "choices": [
      "You should assume posted clearance signs are correct.",
      "The weight of a vehicle changes its height.",
      "If the road surface causes your vehicle to tilt toward objects at the edge of the road, you should drive close to the shoulder."
  ],
  "answer": "The weight of a vehicle changes its height."
},
{
  "question": "64. Which of these is a good rule to follow when using a fire extinguisher?",
  "choices": [
      "Keep as close to the fire as possible.",
      "Stay downwind of the fire.",
      "Aim at the base of the fire."
  ],
  "answer": "Aim at the base of the fire."
},
{
  "question": "65. While driving, you see a small (1-foot square) cardboard box ahead in your lane. You should:",
  "choices": [
      "Steer around it without making a sudden or unsafe move.",
      "Brake hard to avoid hitting it.",
      "Hit it with your vehicle to knock it off the road."
  ],
  "answer": "Steer around it without making a sudden or unsafe move."
},
{
  "question": "66. Is it legal to drive with one fourth of a vehicle's leaf springs broken or missing?",
  "choices": [
      "It doesn't make any difference as long as you go the speed limit.",
      "Yes.",
      "No."
  ],
  "answer": "No."
},
{
  "question": "67. Which of these can cause a fire?",
  "choices": [
      "Loose fuel connections.",
      "Under-inflated tires.",
      "Electrical short circuits.",
      "All the answers are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of the answers are correct."
},
{
  "question": "68. Dry bulk tanks and hanging meat:",
  "choices": [
      "Have low centers of gravity.",
      "Do not require special care.",
      "Are unstable loads."
  ],
  "answer": "Are unstable loads."
},
{
  "question": "69. Which of the following should you NOT do in the event of hydraulic brake failure?",
  "choices": [
      "Shift up.",
      "Use the parking or emergency brake.",
      "Pump the brakes."
  ],
  "answer": "Shift up."
},
{
  "question": "70. To correct a drive-wheel braking skid you should:",
  "choices": [
      "Turn slowly.",
      "Keep your foot off the clutch.",
      "Counter-steer."
  ],
  "answer": "Counter-steer."
},
{
  "question": "71. Which of the following statements about tank vehicles is true?",
  "choices": [
      "All tank vehicles have some sort of bulkhead or baffle.",
      "The term 'tank vehicle' refers only to those vehicles having a permanently attached tank.",
      "Special skills are required to haul liquid tanks."
  ],
  "answer": "Special skills are required to haul liquid tanks."
},
{
  "question": "72. If you are driving a long distance, you should:",
  "choices": [
      "Stop often and take short breaks before you feel really drowsy or tired.",
      "Take a short break once or twice during the trip when you are feeling tired or drowsy.",
      "Avoid short breaks, but keep the window open."
  ],
  "answer": "Stop often and take short breaks before you feel really drowsy or tired."
},
{
  "question": "73. Which of the following is true about a vehicle with a high center of gravity?",
  "choices": [
      "The vehicle is less likely to tip over.",
      "The cargo should be rearranged so that the heaviest parts of the cargo are under the lightest parts.",
      "The vehicle is less dangerous on curves."
  ],
  "answer": "The cargo should be rearranged so that the heaviest parts of the cargo are under the lightest parts."
},
{
  "question": "74. To prevent skidding, you should:",
  "choices": [
      "Brake hard at all stops.",
      "Turn the wheel sharply for all turns.",
      "Adjust to conditions while driving."
  ],
  "answer": "Adjust to conditions while driving."
},
{
  "question": "75. You should back and turn toward the driver's side:",
  "choices": [
      "Unless you would have to drive around the block first.",
      "So you can watch the rear of the vehicle by looking out the side window.",
      "If you do not have someone to help you."
  ],
  "answer": "So you can watch the rear of the vehicle by looking out the side window."
},
{
  "question": "76. When you check the condition of visible parts during your pretrip inspection, make sure that they are secured against snagging, rubbing or wearing.",
  "choices": [
      "Primary and secondary safety cab locks.",
      "Frame and cross members.",
      "Airlines and electrical wiring."
  ],
  "answer": "Airlines and electrical wiring."
},
{
  "question": "77. With a BAC of _, most people lose consciousness, and some die. a. .40 b. .16 c. .10",
  "choices": [
      "a. .40",
      "b. .16",
      "c. .10"
  ],
  "answer": "a. .40"
},
{
  "question": "78. The distance your vehicle travels from the time your eyes see a hazard until your brakes recognize it is called:",
  "choices": [
      "Distance.",
      "Perception.",
      "Reaction.",
      "Braking."
  ],
  "answer": "Perception."
},
{
  "question": "79. Which of these items is checked in a pre-trip inspection?",
  "choices": [
      "Whether all vehicle lights are working and clean.",
      "Cargo securement.",
      "Wiper blades.",
      "All of these answers are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
},
{
  "question": "80. The 'reaction distance' is the distance traveled from the time:",
  "choices": [
      "The brain tells the foot to push the brake pedal to the time the foot actually pushes the pedal.",
      "The eyes see a hazard to the time the brain knows that it is a hazard.",
      "The eyes see a hazard to the time the foot pushes the brake pedal."
  ],
  "answer": "The brain tells the foot to push the brake pedal to the time the foot actually pushes the pedal."
},
{
  "question": "81. When driving a commercial vehicle with a height over 13 feet, you should:",
  "choices": [
      "If you aren't sure a clearance is high enough, stop and make sure.",
      "Not worry about the height clearance as long as you stay on the state or federal highways.",
      "Assume all clearances are high enough."
  ],
  "answer": "If you aren't sure a clearance is high enough, stop and make sure."
},
{
  "question": "82. The purpose of a baffle is to:",
  "choices": [
      "Control the load surge.",
      "Separate the load.",
      "To keep expansion of load down."
  ],
  "answer": "Control the load surge."
},
{
  "question": "83. The new BAC (Blood Alcohol Concentration) for commercial drivers to be considered intoxicated when driving a commercial vehicle is:",
  "choices": [
      "a. .02",
      "b. .06",
      "c. .04"
  ],
  "answer": "c. .04"
},
{
  "question": "84. Truck escape ramps:",
  "choices": [
      "Cannot be used by certain types of heavy vehicles.",
      "Are designed to protect vehicles from damage.",
      "Should not be used unless you have first tried all other ways to save your vehicle after brake failure."
  ],
  "answer": "Are designed to protect vehicles from damage."
},
{
  "question": "85. Which of these can cause the vehicle to skid?",
  "choices": [
      "Not enough weight on the front axle.",
      "Over acceleration.",
      "Turning too sharply.",
      "All of these can cause a vehicle to skid."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these can cause a vehicle to skid."
},
{
  "question": "86. Which of these describes how you should use the brake pedal on a steep downhill grade?",
  "choices": [
      "Release the brake when you are 5 MPH below your safe speed, then let your speed come back up to your safe speed and repeat braking again (bring your speed down 5 MPH below your safe speed).",
      "With stronger pressure as the vehicle goes downhill.",
      "Light steady pressure."
  ],
  "answer": "Release the brake when you are 5 MPH below your safe speed, then let your speed come back up to your safe speed and repeat braking again (bring your speed down 5 MPH below your safe speed)."
},
{
  "question": "87. An en-route inspection should include checking:",
  "choices": [
      "Cargo doors and/or cargo securement.",
      "Tire temperature.",
      "Brake temperature.",
      "All of these should be checked."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these should be checked."
},
{
  "question": "88. According to the driver's manual, why should you limit the use of your horn?",
  "choices": [
      "It wears down the battery.",
      "It can startle other drivers.",
      "The horn is not a good way to let others know you're there."
  ],
  "answer": "It can startle other drivers."
},
{
  "question": "89. The amount of liquid to load into a tank depends on:",
  "choices": [
      "The weight of the liquid.",
      "The legal weight limits.",
      "The amount of liquid will expand in transit.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "90. You should use your mirrors to check:",
  "choices": [
      "Traffic gaps before you merge.",
      "The condition of the tires and cargo.",
      "Where the rear of your vehicle is while you make turns.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "91. Your brakes can get wet when you drive through a heavy rain. What can this cause when the brakes are applied?",
  "choices": [
      "Lack of braking power.",
      "Trailer jackknife.",
      "Wheel lockup.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "92. Which of these statements about using mirrors is true?",
  "choices": [
      "There are blind spots that your mirrors cannot show you.",
      "You should check your mirrors twice for a lane change.",
      "You should look at a mirror for several seconds at a time."
  ],
  "answer": "There are blind spots that your mirrors cannot show you."
},
{
  "question": "93. To avoid a crash, you had to drive onto the right shoulder. You are now driving at 40 MPH on the shoulder. How should you move back onto the pavement?",
  "choices": [
      "Keep moving at the present speed and steer very gently back onto the pavement.",
      "Come to a complete stop, if possible, before steering back onto the pavement.",
      "Brake hard to slow the vehicle, then steer sharply onto the pavement."
  ],
  "answer": "Come to a complete stop, if possible, before steering back onto the pavement."
},
{
  "question": "94. Which of these statements about managing space is true?",
  "choices": [
      "Smaller vehicles require more space to stop than larger ones.",
      "When the road is slippery, you should keep much more space in front of your vehicle.",
      "Many accidents are caused by drivers keeping too much space in front of their vehicles."
  ],
  "answer": "When the road is slippery, you should keep much more space in front of your vehicle."
},
{
  "question": "95. You are testing the stopping action of service brakes on a hydraulic system. Which of these can mean there is a problem?",
  "choices": [
      "The brake pedal goes to the floor.",
      "Stopping action is delayed.",
      "The vehicle pulls to one side when the brake pedal is pressed.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "96. The distance that you should look ahead of your vehicle while driving amounts to about _____ at highway speed.",
  "choices": [
      "1/4 mile.",
      "25 feet.",
      "1 mile."
  ],
  "answer": "1/4 mile."
},
{
  "question": "97. Which of these statements about drinking alcohol is true?",
  "choices": [
      "Alcohol first affects judgment and self-control, which are essential for safe driving.",
      "Statistics show that drivers who have been drinking have a much greater chance of being in a crash.",
      "A driver can lose their license for driving while under the influence of alcohol.",
      "All of these are true."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are true."
},
{
  "question": "98. On which fires can you use the 'ABC' fire extinguisher?",
  "choices": [
      "Electrical fires.",
      "Burning tires.",
      "Burning cloth.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "99. Which of these is a proper use of vehicle lights and flashers?",
  "choices": [
      "Flashing your brake lights to warn someone behind you of a hazard that will require slowing down.",
      "Turning on your headlights during the day when visibility is reduced due to rain or snow.",
      "Flashing your brake lights to warn someone behind you that you are going to stop on the road.",
      "All of these are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "All of these are correct."
},
{
  "question": "100. Which of these tell you that cargo contains hazardous materials?",
  "choices": [
      "A four-inch, diamond-shaped hazardous materials label on the container.",
      "A hazardous materials placard on the vehicle.",
      "Both of these answers are correct.",
      "Neither of these answers are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "Both of these answers are correct."
},
{
  "question": "101. If you are convicted for driving under the influence while driving a commercial vehicle, and this is your first offense, you will most likely get:",
  "choices": [
      "A fine of $500.",
      "Probation for a period of one year.",
      "At least a one-year suspension of your CDL."
  ],
  "answer": "At least a one-year suspension of your CDL."
},
{
  "question": "102. Some liquid tanks are divided into several smaller tanks by:",
  "choices": [
      "Regulators.",
      "Bulkheads.",
      "Baffles."
  ],
  "answer": "Bulkheads."
},
{
  "question": "103. Front-end header boards:",
  "choices": [
      "Block the forward movement of your cargo.",
      "Protect you from your cargo in case of collision.",
      "Both answers are correct."
  ],
  "answer": "Both answers are correct."
},
{
  "question": "104. The height of the vehicle center of gravity is very important for safe handling. A high center of gravity means you are more likely to:",
  "choices": [
      "Rollover.",
      "Stop faster.",
      "Get stuck."
  ],
  "answer": "Rollover."
}
]
